

+995 585-889-511 **♂** khaykingleb.com **③** @khaykingleb\_blog **④** 

# Summary

MLOps/DevOps Engineer with 3.5+ years of software engineering experience. Specialized in boosting model performance, reducing costs by >\$10k monthly, deploying scalable solutions for apps with >30k DAU, and optimizing data and workflow pipelines. Integrated state-of-the-art models and deployed infrastructure across cloud and on-premise environments. Background in infrastructure, speech, natural language processing, and finance.

#### EXPERIENCE

#### MLOps/DevOps Engineer at iClerk

San Francisco, USA (Remote)

Silicon Valley startup focusing on automating tedious tasks for B2B, \$3.4M pre-seed investment

July 2023 — Present

- Refined an ensemble model for speech-to-text and speaker diarization, achieving an 11x speedup and improved accuracy
- o Developed a scalable inference pipeline with NVIDIA Triton, reducing costs by 5x for processing one-hour meetings
- o Secured one of the 1st clients by implementing advanced RAG for efficient parsing of financial statements
- o Architected a K3s GPU cluster with NVIDIA GPU Operator for monitoring and validation, cutting GPU costs by >50%
- Established IaC monitoring & alerting for 4 K8s clusters with Grafana Alloy OTel Collector, reducing downtime and errors

# ML/MLOps Engineer at MynaLabs

Tbilisi, Georgia

 $Generative\ AI\ startup\ with\ \$150M\ and\ \$200M\ B2C\ app\ exits,\ both\ sold\ to\ Snapchat$ 

November 2022 — March 2024

- $\circ$  Built a REST/gRPC API for speech tasks with **priority queuing**, handling **60k+ inference requests** per hour
- Researched and deployed state-of-the-art multilingual, emotional text-to-speech and voice conversion models in 44 kHz
- $\circ~$  Created a service for fast  $\mathbf{speech}~\mathbf{model}$  fine-tuning to any voice in  $\mathbf{under}~\mathbf{1}~\mathbf{minute}$
- Terraformized and migrated speech infrastructure to Kubernetes with >4000 lines of IaC
- Introduced MLOps/DevOps best practices to a 20+ developer engineering division

#### Data Scientist at DiviAI

San Francisco, USA (Remote)

Silicon Valley startup building a financial data aggregator for the US market

September 2021 — July 2022

- Engineered a PySpark pipeline for scraping S&P 500 news to estimate investor sentiment with BERT-like models
- o Developed ETL pipelines that aggregate data from 150+ financial API endpoints
- o Designed a listwise learning-to-rank system for stocks recommendation, enhancing long-short strategy performance
- Adopted a Glicko rating system to rank Russell 3000 CEOs

## **EDUCATION**

## NRU "Higher School of Economics"

Moscow, Russia

B.S. with summa cum laude in Economics and Data Science

September 2018 — July 2022

Relevant coursework: C++, Python, R, Machine Learning 1, Machine Learning 2, Large Scale Machine Learning, Deep Learning,
Deep Learning in Audio Processing, Reinforcement Learning, Calculus, Linear Algebra, Probability Theory, Mathematical Statistics, Stochastic Processes, Econometrics, Microeconometrics, Differential & Difference Equations

#### **PROJECTS**

- o DL for Audio: Implemented and optimized models from scratch (e.g., QuartzNet, FastSpeech, HiFi-GAN)
- Huffman Archiver: Built an ASCII archiver in C++ with a Conan-based auto-build system
- ${\color{gray} \bullet} \ \, \textbf{Stochastic Optimization:} \ \, \textbf{Constructed and tested Particle Swarm Optimization and Genetic Algorithm} \\$

# Miscellaneous

- CFA Level 1: Passed in February 2021, scoring in the top 10% of candidates worldwide
- Teaching Assistant: Facilitated course coordination in Accounting, Probability, Statistics, Machine Learning (2020–2022)

# SKILLS

- Languages: Python, Rust, Go, C++, SQL, TypeScript, JavaScript
- $\circ\,$  Frontend: Remix, React, Tailwind, DaisyUI, Vite, Vercel
- o Backend: gRPC, REST, Websocket, Webhook, AsyncIO, FastAPI, Pydantic, JWT, Node.js
- o DevOps: Terraform, Ansible, Docker, Kubernetes, K3s, AWS, GCP, Grafana, Prometheus, Loki, Nginx, Acme, ArgoCD, CI/CD
- o MLOps: DVC, NVIDIA Triton, Ollama, LangChain, TorchScript, ONNX, TensorRT, CoreML, Gradio
- o **DE**: Hadoop, Spark, Databricks, Polars, Kafka, Celery, RabbitMQ
- o Storage: Redis, PostgreSQL, PGVector, Sqitch, S3, R2, Supabase, Airtable
- o R&D: PyTorch, Lightning, Hydra, W&B, Scikit-learn, Numpy, Pandas, SciPy